二零二五年，陕西省初中学业水平。
考试英语听力部分。
二零二五年陕西省初中学业水平考试
英语听力部分。
第一大题，听选答案。
第一节。
听下面十段对话，每段对话后有一个问题，读两遍。
请根据每段对话的内容和后面的问题，从所给的三个选项中
选出问题的正确答案。
1. Peter, please take it easy in this exam.
Thank you, Ms.
2. What does Ms.
Wang ask a boy to do?
Peter, please take it easy in this exam.
Thank you, Ms.
Wang. What does Ms.
Wang ask a boy to do?
2. Your handwriting is so nice.
Thanks, Ms. How is the boy's
Your handwriting is so nice.
Thanks, Ms. 5.
How is the boy's handwriting?
3. Hi, Li Fei.
You look stronger than before.
How did you do that?
By swimming. Question.
How did the man get stronger?
Hi, Li Fei.
You look stronger than before.
How did you do that?
By swimming. Question.
How did the man get stronger?
4. Can I go for a picnic with my friends in the park,
Sure. You'd better come back early.
Question. Where will the girl have the picnic?
Can I go for a picnic with my friends in the park,
Sure. You'd better come back early.
Question. Where will the girl have the picnic?
5. Good evening, sir.
May I take your order?
I'd like some dumplings, please.
What does the man want to order?
Good evening, sir.
May I take your order?
I'd like some dumplings, please.
does the man want to order?
6. What a fine day!
It makes me happy.
Me too. Let's go and play outside.
Question. How do the two speakers feel?
What a fine day!
It makes me happy.
Me too. Let's go and play outside.
Question. How do the two speakers feel?
7. You look cool in this cap.
Is it expensive?
so expensive. It was on sale.
I only paid 20 yuan.
Question. How much did the man pay?
You look cool in this cap.
Is it expensive?
No, so expensive.
It was on sale.
I only paid 20 yuan.
Question. How much did the man pay?
8. Happy birthday, Tom!
Here is my gift for you.
Thank you, Liuli.
I like it very much.
Question. Whose birthday is it?
Happy birthday, Tom!
Here is my gift for you.
Thank you, Liuli.
I like it very much.
Question. Whose birthday is it?
9. I have a stomachache, doctor.
What should I do?
Drink some hot water and don't eat too much cold food in
Question. Who are the two speakers?
9. I have a stomachache, doctor.
What should I do?
Drink some hot water and don't eat too much cold food in
Question. Who are the two speakers?
10. Hi, I find reading books is just like going on a journey.
No wonder I often see you in the school library these days.
Question. What does the girl often do these days?
Hi, I find reading books is just like going on a journey.
No wonder I often see you in the school library these days.
Question. What does the often do these days?
第二节：听下面两段材料，包括一段对话和一段独白。
每段材料后有几道小题，
请根据材料的内容，从题目所给。
的三个选项中选出问题的正确答案。
每段材料读两遍。
听第一段材料。
回答第十一、十二小题。
Look! Many students are running to the playground.
What are they doing?
They are having safety practice.
What do they often do in the practice?
They learn some safety skills.
This time, the practice is about running quickly away from fire and putting out
fire. That's meaningful.
How often do they have safety practice?
Once a month.
Students need to know more about safety.
I really agree.
Look! Many students are running to the playground.
What are they doing?
They are having safety practice.
What do they often do in the practice?
They learn some safety skills.
This time, the practice is about running quickly away from fire and putting out
fire. That's meaningful.
How often do they have safety practice?
Once a month.
Students need to know more about safety.
I really agree.
听第二段材料，回答第十三至十五。
五小题。
Hi, Phillips. I'm sending you this message to tell you good news.
You did a good job in the robot competition in our school.
Congratulations! You won second place.
We really like your robot.
We have a prize for you.
You can get it from your science teacher Mr.
at Robotics Club on Friday.
Hi, Phillips. I'm sending you this message to tell you good news.
You did a good job in the robot competition in our school.
Congratulations! You won second place.
We really like your robot.
We have a prize for you.
You can get it from your science teacher Mr.
at Robotics Club on Friday.
第二大题：听填信息。
本题你将听到一段独白，读两遍，
请根据独白内容，用所听到的信息完成下列个体，
每空不超过三个单词。
Do you drink milk for breakfast before you go to school?
Many students drink milk every morning.
As we know, things such as cheese, yogurt and so on are made from milk.
People call them milk products.
They are helpful for our body.
Milk is important to humans, especially to new babies.
They can drink milk at birth.
can come from a baby's mother.
Milk can also come from an animal,
like a cow or a goat.
Milk can help new babies grow quickly.
It can also help protect babies from getting sick.
Milk is rich in Calcium,
C -A -L -C -I -U -M,
is something all humans need in their bodies.
Calcium keeps our teeth and bones strong.
There are also many other good things in milk.
These good things can make us stay healthy and strong.
More importantly, they help students do better at school.
Do you drink milk for breakfast before you go to school?
Many students drink milk every morning.
As we know, things such as cheese, yogurt and so on are made from milk.
People call them milk products.
They are helpful for our body.
Milk is important to humans, especially to new babies.
They can drink milk at birth.
can come from a baby's mother.
Milk can also come from an animal,
like a cow or a goat.
Milk can help new babies grow quickly.
It can also help protect babies from getting sick.
Milk is rich in Calcium, C -A -L -C -I -U -M,
is something all humans need in their bodies.
Calcium keeps our teeth and bones strong.
There are also many other good things in
These good things can make us stay healthy and strong.
More importantly, they help students do better at school.
This is the end
听力部分到此结束。
现在，请同学们将所选答案转涂在答题卡的相应位置，然后继续作答笔试
部分试题。